{"animal":{"subcategories":{"General Animals":[{"question":"Which animal is known to have the most powerful bite?","options":["Mouse","Crocodile","Hippopotamus","Lion"],"correct":"Hippopotamus","points":100},{"question":"Which of these animals is the fastest land animal?","options":["Tiger","Cheetah","Horse","Ostrich"],"correct":"Cheetah","points":200},{"question":"Which of these animals is found only in the Arctic?","options":["Polar bear","Penguin","Leopard seal","Walrus"],"correct":"Polar bear","points":300},{"question":"Which animal can regenerate its limbs?","options":["Crab","Gecko","Octopus","Starfish"],"correct":"Starfish","points":400}],"Mammals":[{"question":"What is the largest mammal on Earth?","options":["Elephant","Blue Whale","Giraffe","Lion"],"correct":"Blue Whale","points":100},{"question":"Which mammal has the longest gestation period?","options":["Horse","Elephant","Blue Whale","Rhinoceros"],"correct":"Elephant","points":200},{"question":"Which mammal can fly?","options":["Flying Squirrel","Sugar Glider","Bat","None"],"correct":"Bat","points":300},{"question":"Which mammal has the most teeth?","options":["Giant Armadillo","Orangutans","Otter","Orca"],"correct":"Giant Armadillo","points":400}],"Fish":[{"question":"What fish has the ability to produce electric shocks?","options":["Electric Eel","Star fish","Stingray","Catfish"],"correct":"Electric Eel","points":100},{"question":"What type of fish is known for being able to inflate its body when threatened?","options":["Puffer fish","Barracuda","Clownfish","Angelfish"],"correct":"Puffer fish","points":200},{"question":"What fish can survive on land for short periods by breathing through its skin?","options":["Eel","Lungfish","Mud skipper","Carp"],"correct":"Mud skipper","points":300},{"question":"Which fish is famous for its ability to change sex?","options":["Clownfish","Angler fish","Shark","Piranha"],"correct":"Clownfish","points":400}],"Reptiles":[{"question":"Which reptile can change the color of its skin to blend into its surroundings?","options":["Iguana","Chameleon","Gecko","Crocodile"],"correct":"Chameleon","points":100},{"question":"What reptile is the heaviest snake in the world?","options":["King Cobra","Anaconda","Python","Boa Constrictor"],"correct":"Anaconda","points":200},{"question":"How do snakes smell their surroundings?","options":["Through their nostrils","By flicking their tongue","Through their skin","By sensing vibrations"],"correct":"By flicking their tongue","points":300},{"question":"What is the term for reptiles that live in trees?","options":["Arboreal","Terrestrial","Aquatic","Fossorial"],"correct":"Arboreal","points":400}]}},"plant":{"subcategories":{"Flowers":[{"question":"What flower is traditionally associated with love and romance?","options":["Daisy","Tulip","Rose","Lily"],"correct":"Rose","points":100},{"question":"What flower is known for its ability to track the movement of the sun?","options":["Poppy","Daisy","Lily","Sunflower"],"correct":"Sunflower","points":200},{"question":"What is the official flower of Japan, often associated with the spring season?","options":["Chrysanthemum","Sakura (Cherry Blossom)","Azalea","Magnolia"],"correct":"Sakura (Cherry Blossom)","points":300},{"question":"Which flower is known for blooming once every 12 years in India?","options":["Neelakurinji","Lotus","Jasmine","Dahlia"],"correct":"Neelakurinji","points":400}],"Trees":[{"question":"What type of tree produces acorns?","options":["Maple","Oak","Pine","Birch"],"correct":"Oak","points":100},{"question":"What tree is known as the tallest tree species in the world?","options":["Sequoia","Douglas Fir","Giant Cedar","Coast Redwood"],"correct":"Coast Redwood","points":200},{"question":"What is the term for trees that lose their leaves in the fall?","options":["Perennial","Coniferous","Deciduous","Evergreen"],"correct":"Deciduous","points":300},{"question":"What tree grows the fastest and is often used for paper production?","options":["Bamboo","Pine","Poplar","Maple"],"correct":"Bamboo","points":400}],"Edible":[{"question":"Which fruit is the primary ingredient in guacamole?","options":["Mango","Lime","Tomato","Avocado"],"correct":"Avocado","points":100},{"question":"What legume is used to make hummus?","options":["Lentil","Black Bean","Chickpea","Kidney Bean"],"correct":"Chickpea","points":200},{"question":"Which herb is often paired with tomatoes in Italian cuisine?","options":["Dill","Chives","Oregano","Sage"],"correct":"Oregano","points":300},{"question":"What ancient grain is sometimes called 'the mother of all grains'?","options":["Amaranth","Millet","Quinoa","Spelt"],"correct":"Quinoa","points":400}],"Plant Anatomy":[{"question":"What vascular tissue in plants transports water from the roots to the leaves?","options":["Phloem","Xylem","Cambium","Cortex"],"correct":"Xylem","points":100},{"question":"Which part of a plant contains the reproductive organs?","options":["Flower","Stem","Roots","Leaves"],"correct":"Flower","points":200},{"question":"What is the waxy layer that covers a leaf and helps prevent water loss?","options":["Cuticle","Epidermis","Cortex","Mesophyll"],"correct":"Cuticle","points":300},{"question":"In which layer of the leaf does most photosynthesis occur?","options":["Spongy Mesophyll","Epidermis","Vein","Palisade Mesophyll"],"correct":"Palisade Mesophyll","points":400}]}},"culture":{"subcategories":{"Language":[{"question":"Which language is the most spoken in the world?","options":["Spanish","English","Mandarin Chinese","French"],"correct":"Mandarin Chinese","points":100},{"question":"What is the official language of Brazil?","options":["Spanish","Portuguese","Mandarin Chinese","French"],"correct":"Portuguese","points":200},{"question":"Which language has the most words in its vocabulary?","options":["German","English","Japanese","Latin"],"correct":"English","points":300},{"question":"What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?","options":["Oxymoron","Homophone","Anagram","Palindrome"],"correct":"Palindrome","points":400}],"Art":[{"question":"Who painted the famous artwork 'The Starry Night'?","options":["Pablo Picasso","Claude Monet","Vincent van Gogh","Leonardo da Vinci"],"correct":"Vincent van Gogh","points":100},{"question":"Which famous sculptor created the statue of David?","options":["Donatello","Michelangelo","Francis Bacon","Raphael"],"correct":"Michelangelo","points":200},{"question":"Who painted the 'School of Athens,' featuring ancient Greek philosophers?","options":["Raphael","Rembrandt","Caravaggio","Eugène Delacroix"],"correct":"Raphael","points":300},{"question":"What type of art is characterized by the use of geometric shapes and abstract forms?","options":["Cubism","Surrealism","Impressionism","Realism"],"correct":"Cubism","points":400}],"Literature":[{"question":"Which play by William Shakespeare is about the tragic love story of two young lovers from feuding families?","options":["Hamlet","Macbeth","Othello","Romeo and Juliet"],"correct":"Romeo and Juliet","points":100},{"question":"Who is the author of the fantasy series 'The Lord of the Rings'?","options":["J.R.R. Tolkien","C.S. Lewis","George R.R. Martin","J.K. Rowling"],"correct":"J.R.R. Tolkien","points":200},{"question":"What is the term for a novel or story that is set in an idealized version of the past or future?","options":["Dystopia","Utopia","Allegory","Parable"],"correct":"Moby-Dick","points":300},{"question":"What is the term for a recurring subject, theme, or symbol in a work of literature?","options":["Allegory","Theme","Motif","Imagery"],"correct":"Motif","points":400}],"Pop Culture":[{"question":"Who is known as the 'King of Pop'?","options":["Michael Jackson","Prince","Elvis Presley","Justin Timberlake"],"correct":"Michael Jackson","points":100},{"question":"Which 1980s film featured a young boy named Marty McFly who traveled through time in a DeLorean?","options":["Ghostbusters","Back to the Future","The Goonies","E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial"],"correct":"Back to the Future","points":200},{"question":"Who is the former Friends star who became a successful producer and entrepreneur with her company 'The Honest Company'?","options":["Courteney Cox","Jennifer Aniston","Lisa Kudrow","Jessica Alba"],"correct":"Jessica Alba","points":300},{"question":"In the Harry Potter series, what is the name of Harry's owl?","options":["Errol","Pigwidgeon","Hermes","Hedwig"],"correct":"Hedwig","points":400}]}},"history":{"subcategories":{"Historical Discoveries":[{"question":"Who is credited with discovering the laws of gravity after observing an apple fall from a tree?","options":["Isaac Newton","Albert Einstein","Nikola Tesla","Galileo Galilei"],"correct":"Isaac Newton","points":100},{"question":"In 1492, which explorer sailed across the Atlantic and 'discovered' the Americas?","options":["Marco Polo","Christopher Columbus ","Ferdinand Magellan","Hernán Cortés"],"correct":"Christopher Columbus ","points":200},{"question":"Which scientist discovered the law of planetary motion and is known for his work on elliptical orbits?","options":["Isaac Newton","Galileo Galilei","Johannes Kepler","Albert Einstein"],"correct":"Johannes Kepler","points":300},{"question":"In 1953, James Watson and Francis Crick discovered the structure of which molecule?","options":["Enzymes","Proteins","RNA","DNA"],"correct":"DNA","points":400}],"Historical Figures":[{"question":"Who was the first President of the United States?","options":["Thomas Jefferson","Benjamin Franklin","George Washington","Abraham Lincoln"],"correct":"George Washington","points":100},{"question":"Which British prime minister served during World War II and is known for his leadership and speeches during the war?","options":["Winston Churchill","Margaret Thatcher","Tony Blair","David Cameron"],"correct":"Winston Churchill","points":200},{"question":"Who was the first explorer to successfully sail around the world, completing his voyage in 1522?","options":["Francis Drake","John Cabot","Vasco da Gama","Ferdinand Magellan"],"correct":"Ferdinand Magellan","points":300},{"question":"Who was the first person to travel to the North Pole, completing the journey in 1909?","options":["Ernest Shackleton","Robert Peary","Roald Amundsen","Sir Edmund Hillary"],"correct":"Robert Peary","points":400}],"Historical Eras":[{"question":"What ancient civilization, known for its pyramids, hieroglyphs, and mummification practices, thrived along the Nile River from around 3000 BCE to 30 BCE?","options":["Ancient Greece","Ancient Egypt","The Indus Valley","The Sumerians"],"correct":"Ancient Egypt","points":100},{"question":"What era, beginning in the late 18th century, saw major industrialization, technological advancements, and the transition from agrarian societies to industrial ones?","options":["The Industrial Revolution","The Age of Enlightenment","The Age of Exploration","The Age of Reason"],"correct":"The Industrial Revolution","points":200},{"question":"The 1960s and 1970s were marked by global social, political, and cultural upheaval, including civil rights movements, protests, and major advances in technology. This era is often called what?","options":["The Great Depression Era","The Space Race Era","The Gilded Age","The Counterculture Era"],"correct":"The Counterculture Era","points":300},{"question":"The period from the mid-15th century to the early 17th century, characterized by the widespread exploration, expansion, and colonization of the Americas by European powers, is known as what?","options":["The Age of Discovery","The Age of Enlightenment","The Age of Empires","The Medieval Era"],"correct":"The Age of Discovery","points":400}],"World History":[{"question":"Which period of time from 1914 to 1918 saw major global conflict, involving many of the world's great powers, and resulted in massive casualties and the redrawing of borders?","options":["World War II","World War I","The Cold War","The Napoleonic Wars"],"correct":"World War I","points":100},{"question":"What was the primary goal of the Crusades, a series of religious wars fought between the 11th and 15th centuries?","options":["To spread Christianity","To conquer the Americas","To establish the British Empire","To control the Holy Land"],"correct":"To control the Holy Land","points":200},{"question":"The Roman Empire expanded across Europe, Asia, and North Africa. Who was its first emperor?","options":["Julius Caesar","Constantine","Augustus Caesar","Nero"],"correct":"Augustus Caesar","points":300},{"question":"The Berlin Wall, which separated East and West Germany, fell in which year?","options":["1985","1989","1991","2001"],"correct":"1989","points":400}]}}}